

#### Address:

1400 Walmer Road, Toronto, ON M5P 2X7, Canada

Email: austin.collie.co@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/austincOllie



### Skills

- 1. Language
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- PHP
- 2. Frameworks and libraries
- React, Next, Gatsby
- Redux, Mobx
- Vue, Nuxt, Vuex
- Angular
- Node
- Laravel, Symfony
- Bootstrap, Tailwind
- 3. Devops and Tools
- AWS, Heroku, Firebase
- Docker, Git
- CI/CD
- 4. Paradigms
- Full Stack Development
- Agile Software Development

# **Austin Collie**

### Full Stack Developer



### Profile

I am a Full-Stack Web Development with over 8+ years of experience and a deep passion for programming.

Creative, Innovative, Highly Motivated Full-Stack Web Developer who loves to learn new technologies and creatively solve problems

My attention to detail and perfectionist attitude has always helped me do my job effectively and efficiently. I'm a full stack, polyglot developer who is constantly learning how to make web/hybrid apps faster, leaner, and perfectly designed.

Summarizing my experience and skills, I have worked as a Software Engineer with more than 8 years of solid experience in IT, focusing principally on full-stack development using Javascript, PHP, and Javascript frameworks.



### Work Exprience

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Self Employed - Full Time Jun 2021 - Present

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

ELEKS - Full Time May 2018 - Jun 2021

- Built rich SPAs using Vue/Nuxt, React, Angular.
- Updated main architecture of current admin project with React and React redux.
- Bulit eCommerce application using React, Node, Firebase, Salesforce and Twilio API.
- Set up the AWS environment (AWS S3, AWS CloudFront, and AWS EC2, Route53, RDS)
- Decreased the complexity with optimize algorithms and structure
- Developed new features in a message board written in Vue and Laravel
- Developed PWA healthcare web app for booking between patients/doctors with Angular + AWS amplify

## **Austin Collie**

Full Stack Developer



### Work Experience

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Avenga - Full Time Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

- Designed architecture and developed eSports app with React(Next.js), Redux, and Ant design.
- Implemented a large front-end application in Vue according to wireframes as well as a back-end in PHP/Laravel
- Added data visualization pages with High charts/D3.
- Designed database architecture and API based on PostgreSQL, Express.js
- Worked with chart libraries such as highchart, tradingview
- Implemented Unti Testing with Jest (90% coverage)
- Made Swagger documentation

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Clean Group - Full Time Jan 2014 - Aug 2016

- Implemented messages and files receiving logic using webhooks and events subscription
- Helped front-end developers with Vue.js apps and other JS + HTML + CSS tasks
- Implemented messages and files sending logic using platform API calls
- Implemented app analytics, designed a lot of complex database queries, and performed optimization and caching
- Implemented an asynchronous long-polling service for receiving chat events using React



### Academic Background

#### **ONTARIO TECH UNIVERSITY**

Master's Degree of Computer Science 2009 - 2013